I mean, some Soyuz, rides have been as little as
like, six hours, right?
Relatively easy.
Going to space is only rocket science.
Don't want to trivialize.
It's still, and even that's the—
you even have to admonish myself—
it's still not easy to go to space.
It's still, I mean,
it is rocket—rocket science—it's literal rocket
science,
which is hugely complex,
and there's always inherent
risk,
and all these other things.
But when you start comparing it to,
you know, going to Mars,
or, you know,
our far-flung aspirations of spreading,
throughout the the solar system,
and the galaxy and everything,
when you compare it to that,
it's, you know,
doing hand quotes easy,
but it's still a monumental undertaking.
Yeah, and that's why.
So we're doing that, just like you said.
In the future,
we want to go farther, right?
So we want to go to Mars.
We want to really just expand
our, presence in the solar system.
So, the International Space Station is a great,
way to practice that.
It's a good—like,
you have a good understanding of what,
it takes to live in space,
to operate in space.
You could do a ton of science,
and learn how things interact.
And then, if you learn how things interact,
you can design,
better systems to make them work better.
I think one of the ones,
I think capillary action,
I think, was a was a great one.
Like, the way that fluids move in,
in space is kind of cool,
because they—
It's sort of like create a ball,
and there's no down.
So if you're trying to design,
like, a system that,
like, a rocket system,
in order to propel fuel,
you need to—the fuel isn't
going to go down, right?
It, kind of needs to have that sort of capillary,
action and a path to get there.
Like, little—those little tiny things are things,
that make the huge difference in being, able to
kind of explore the solar system.
Well, it all comes to down to—
Gravity, and that's kind of the ultimate,
differentiator between,
why everything we do in outer,
space is different from the way,
we do it on Earth.
Totally, some of the stuff you touch on
is—is very apt.
I mean, just moving fluids where—
You know, here on Earth,
we almost, take it for granted that everything,
settles towards the bottom.
So plumbing systems and everything—
you can use that to your advantage.
In space, you don't have that,
and that affects everything—from
moving rocket fuel to—
You know, I'm an astronaut,
and I need to get a drink of water.
Well, that system has to be specifically,
designed to work in the absence of gravity.
And we've had a lot of practice,
you know, since we've been flying in space.
Space, since since the sixties,
but the station is really the first,
place you've had.
On this scale,
there have been
space stations in the past,
both from the U.S. and Russia.
But the space,
station is really the the modern,
cutting-edge test bed for just doing and,
learning everything about
living in space.
And so you have
all of these, different technologies,
that—like I said earlier—everything,
you do in space is different from,
the way that you do it on planet Earth,
where, you know,
you have.